Credits to /u/ilfans for the translation, thank you!
Enjoy watching :)
Pod 153: Everything that lives is designed to end.
"We" are perpetually trapped ...
... in a never-ending spiral of life and death.
Is this a curse?
Or some kind of punishment?
I often think about the god who blessed us with this cryptic puzzle ...
... and wonder if "we'll" ever have the chance to kill him.
(September 5th)
Pod 042: Unit 2B's vital signs confirmed.
Memory storage, thought circuits, auxiliary motor
functions, all confirmed to have been restarted.
Entering reboot sequence.
Good morning, 2B.
2B: I ...
Pod 042: Report: Unit 2B was killed by unit A2 approximately 1718 hours ago.
2B: 1718 hours ago ... So ... 72 days, then.
Pod 042: Following that, us tactical support units reconstructed your parts.
The virus previously inside you deactivated along
with the tower's collapse, and remains in suspension.
2B: Tower ...? What happened ...?
Ah!! 9S ...!!
Pod 153: Report: Unit 9S ceased activity approximately 740 hours ago.
2B: Pod ... 153?
Pod 153: Unit 9S was severely contaminated, however said virus
deactivated along with the tower's collapse, and remains in suspension.
2B: So he's just ... asleep?
Pod 153: Negative: An error occurred during unit 9S's reboot sequence.
2B: What do you mean, an error ...?
Pod 153: Unknown: All checks were completed, however his personal data
will not begin loading procedures, causing an inability to reboot.
2B: His personal data won't load ... Then in that case, run
the monitoring sequence, and skip the check sequence ...
Pod 153: Negative: This unit has already attempted 345
combinations 34,500 times, and all have ended in failure.
Pod 153: Unit 9S's current state suggests there is a possibility
his personal data has been lost due to some unknown cause.
2B: His personal data is ... lost ...?
Pod 153: Proposal: Unit 2B should consider disposing of unit 9S's body.
2B: There's no way I could ... just dispose of his body ...!
Pod 153: ... Understood.
2B: After being reconstructed, there wasn't even a hint of dirt on 9S's body ...
His face ... looked just like he was sleeping.
I took my weapon in hand, and packed the minimum
necessary provisions, before standing up.
I had to go.
There had to be a way to get 9S to reboot properly.
That's what I believed.
September 14th.
2B: I received information on what happened while I was gone from the pods.
About A2 ... and 9S.
I also heard about how the two of them destroyed some huge
"Tower" that had been created by the machine lifeforms.
The rubble from it is still scattered all throughout the city.
The City Ruins' landscape had been completely changed.
Pod 042: Proposal: Unit 2B should gather information at the resistance camp.
2B: The resistance camp was able to miraculously
avoid damage from the collapse of the tower ...
However Devola and Popola, and a few others in the
resistance, lost their lives in the fight with the machines.
Even though Anemone was faced with such a difficult
situation, she still remained level-headed.
I tried speaking to Anemone about the situation with 9S's rebooting,
but she wasn't able to provide me with any helpful information.
Pod 153: Report: Relevant records within the Bunker have been lost.
2B: We YoRHa units are a special type.
We contain something other androids don't within us — a Black Box.
And due to that, we're capable of much higher functionality.
However, unlike general androids, our maintenance
is only able to be done on the Bunker.
It's possible to make easy repairs with the small amount of materials and programs at access points,
but detailed information about the insides of our bodies was lost along with the fall of the Bunker.
Even so, I was traveling from place to place looking for the information I needed.
No matter ... how long it took.
Pod 042: Alert: Unit 2B is taking damage due to maintenance failure.
Proposal: Unit 2B should perform proper repair and replenish materials.
2B: With how tired I was, even doing simple first aid felt troublesome.
In the depths of my heart, I started to feel
like ... everything I was doing was meaningless.
I don't ... care anymore.
I wonder if ... 9S will ever wake up.
That sort of dark thought process began to take over.
And I shook my head.
I couldn't give up. I couldn't give up. I couldn't give up.
Even if I was just deceiving myself, I couldn't admit that.
It caused my body to become heavy.
If I go further away from here, I may be
able to find surviving YoRHa members.
Pod 153: Report: Mail notification received.
2B: ... Check it.
Pod 153: Sender: Jackass.
Subject: About 9S's Personal Data Reboot.
Yo, how's it going, 2B?
I know a little something about 9S's condition.
I've been looking into a lot of things since everything
happened, and I came across some concerning information.
There were some logs remaining in the access port outside of 9S's memory storage.
They were a communication record from the "Ark" object those machine lifeforms made.
I don't know anything about that "Ark" thing, but it might be some sort of server.
I'll send you the time and coordinates that were written in that log right away.
There might be a hint somewhere in them.
This concludes the body of the email. Time and
three-dimensional coordinate data is attached.
2B: Those coordinates ... were right in the area where the Tower collapsed.