Credits to /u/ilfans for the translation, thank you!
Enjoy watching :)
Pod 042 : Everything that lives is designed to end
"They" are perpetually trapped ...
... in a never-ending spiral of life and death.
Is this a curse?
Or some kind of punishment?
"They" often think about the god who blessed "them" with this cryptic puzzle ...
... and wonder if they'll ever have the chance to kill him.
2B: When I met him "that time",
it was during our mission to destroy the Goliath-class weapon.
9S: You're 2B, right?
My name's 9S. I'm here to provide support.
2B: The No.9 Type S model is a high-end model.
And it's because of that there's a constant danger of
them coming into contact with confidential information.
That's why I've been tasked with the duty of eliminating him ...
Over ... and over ...
But ... The 9S of that time, he was somewhat different.
9S: Scanners like me mostly work alone. Scouting out enemy lines and all that?
So, I don't usually get a partner. It's kind of fun!
2B: I simply ignored him when he'd speak.
If I were to grow close to him, it'd only become more difficult to kill him.
Even so, he wouldn't stop trying to make conversation with me.
9S: Say, 2B? Don't you think this white flower would look good on you?
2B: I have no need for it.
9S: Aw, are you sure?
2B: Attaching a plant to my hair would do nothing for my combat abilities.
Rather, it would more likely cause maintenance failure.
9S: Hahah. Man, 2B, you're way too serious, you know that?
2B : I made a promise with 9S in the past.
A promise that I'd continue to kill him, without fail.
The 9S from back then, and the 9S before me are two different people.
That fact ... makes my chest tighten.
Pod 042: Pod 042 to YoRHa unit 2B.
Report: Detecting errors occurring within unit 2B's memory
region, likely due to unstable psychological state.
Proposal: Moderate rest should cause improvement.
2B: I've already been aware of that for a long time ...
But ... the day I'm freed from this pain ... will be the day I die.
Pod 042: Mail notification received from Command.
2B: I wonder if I was afraid.
Or perhaps... I was wrong.
Even so, I continued on by his side, without even knowing the name of the emotion I'd been feeling.
9S: 2B and I first met in one of the hallways in the Bunker.
I'd received an announcement from the Commander that I'd be working with a partner this time.
However... I was a little uneasy about it.
Scanner models like me usually work alone. And ...
I'd always gotten the impression that No.2 models were somewhat cold.
So when she said those things to me in the hallway, I was ... kind of surprised.
2B: 9S?
9S: Yeah?
2B: Thank you...
For uploading my data to the Bunker.
9S: I’m sorry... I don’t have any memory of doing that.
There wasn't a whole lot of bandwidth down there, you know?
I probably only had enough time to back up your memories.
Mine are only intact up to the point just before we rendezvoused.
2B: ... I see.
9S: Things started out so awkward. At least, until that day ...
It happened after a battle.
Pod 042: Confirming the annihilation of all machine lifeforms in this area.
9S: Whew ...
2B: So we've destroyed every machine lifeform here?
Pod 042: Affirmative: No responses from any machine lifeforms in this area.
2B: Understood.
9S: Huh? Hey, 2B ... did something happen to your right hand?
2B: My right hand ...? Oh, this. I must've injured my finger during the previous battle.
9S: Gah! You're — You're bleeding!
Pod! Get me staunching gel and logic-virus vaccines! Then — uh —
Pod 042: Inadvisable. There is a high probability that excessive
treatment will cause a decrease in movement efficiency to the unit ...
9S: Just shut up and do it already!
2B: ... 9S, don't you think you're overreacting?
9S: Huh? Not you too, 2B!
2B: Just leave it. The nano machines will heal it just fine on their own.
9S: Er, I guess so ...
Pod 042: Confirmation of mission completion by enemy annihilation.
Recommendation: Report results to Command.
9S: Um ... 2B?
2B: What is it?
9S: You think we could at least use the staunching gel?
If contaminants enter the blood stream they'll be difficult to remove, and if it's just staunching
gel, then it shouldn't cause any problems to your motor functions, so, you know, just in case ...
2B: ... All right.
9S: Got it! Then I'll go ahead and prepare it right away!
9S: Now where's that case ...
2B: 9S.
9S: Yeah?
2B: ... Thank you.
9S: I can't remember anymore what my response was when she said that.
Just that I was so happy to be useful to someone.
What was most important to me ... was being together with 2B.
... At least.
Until the day that YoRHa fell, along with the Bunker ...
Pod 042: Large-scale attack ended in failure. The Bunker has collapsed.
Black-box signal for YoRHa unit 2B offline. Death confirmed.
A large "tower" produced by machine lifeforms rose within the city ruins.
Having lost a place to return to, unit 9S aimed
for nothing more than the top of that "tower".
In order to destroy the machine lifeforms which caused this nightmare.
And to end himself as well.
9S: I have to ... apply the vaccine ...
Pod 042: The virus corrodes his body.
His thought process breaks down.
Sound recordings found in the flooded city play back in his mind.
2B: 9S ... The time I was able to spend with you ...
It was like memories of pure light ...
Thank you ... Nine ... s ...
Pod 042: Those memories are his greatest treasure.
Living together, fighting together.
They were like a family.
9S: 2B ...
Pod 042: 9S holds that recording deep within his heart.
Treating it as if it were truly a treasure.
9S: 2B ... I ... I'll be with you before long ...
Pod 042: Reality and fiction blend together.
With clouded consciousness, unit 9S carries himself forward, his legs heavy.
He'll defeat as many enemies as possible, even if he is alone.
As if in response to that wish, a new enemy appears.
Many enemies appear in front of him.
They're ... androids.
They're ... YoRHa units.
9S: 2B models?
Pod 042: The person he treasures above all else.
Someone who resides in a location out of his reach.
I'm glad I got to see you here. I truly am.
I'll tear you apart ... Every last one of you!
Pod 042: 9S draws his sword.
Pod 042: Is this an act of murderous intent? Or is it
perhaps done out of love? It's no longer possible to tell.
Pod 042: Contamination from the logic virus is getting worse.
Nearly 80% of his memory is contaminated, and his thought circuits are severely damaged.
9S: Dammit ... I can't ... remove ...
The vaccine ... it'll no longer ...
Pod 042: Unit 9S knows that there's only one solution left that could dispel the contamination.
To lock his personal data and reformat his entire system.
To throw away all of his current memories, and be reborn anew.
9S: No !... I can't do that ...
No matter how contaminated I become ... I can't lose this memory ...
If that's my only choice ... then I'm better off dead!
Pod 042: 9S is fighting with fear itself.
To have one's personal data contaminated means to lose one's ability to think for themself.
To androids, that is a fate worse than death.
9S: I am who I am ... because of 2B ...
I have a reason to live ... because of those memories ...
So ... please ... don't take them from me ...
Pod 042: To him, calling her his family was much too silly.
But calling her his lover was much too distant.
9S: Machines ... A2 ... It doesn't matter ... I'll kill every last one of you!
2B ...
I ...
Pod 042: Within the corners of his eroding consciousness,
9S continues to protect his memories of 2B.
Even if ... his actions are completely meaningless in the eyes of the world.
2B: I am ... No.2 ... Type E.
I was created to execute my fellow YoRHa soldiers.
9S: I'd already ...
I'd already realized that ...
2B: The mission I had been assigned over and over again...
Was to kill you, 9S.
9S: Stop it ... Enough already ... 2B.
Even if you were trying to kill me, I ...
Being with you, it truly ...
... It felt like I'd found a family.
2B: Hey ... 9S?
I wonder ... Were the choices we made wrong?
Pod 042: Within a pure white tower.
A small boy walks.
Suffering. Uneasy.
Holding within him many small, important memories.
They're of ... the time the two of them spent together.
His memories of those days ... were most precious to him.